<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neural Network Night</title>
    <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Neural Network Night</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Neural Networking Night, 2024 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sep 6th, 2024 - Guy Bouvier</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/guybouvier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/guybouvier/</guid>
      <description>Institut des Neurosciences Paris‑Saclay&#xA;Title of Guy&amp;rsquo;s talks Abstract to appear here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oct 4th, 2024 - Charlotte Le Mouel</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/charlottelemouel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/charlottelemouel/</guid>
      <description>Institut Systèmes Intelligents et de Robotique - ISIR&#xA;Title of Charlotte&amp;rsquo;s talk to be announced Abstract will appear here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nov 8th, 2024 - Jérémie Barral</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeremiebarral/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeremiebarral/</guid>
      <description>Institut de l&amp;rsquo;Audition&#xA;Title of Jérémie&amp;rsquo;s talk to be announced Abstract will appear here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dec 13th, 2024 - Sophie Bagur</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sophiebagur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sophiebagur/</guid>
      <description>ESPCI Paris&#xA;Title to be announced Abstract will appear here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jan 10th, 2025 - Jean-Rémi King</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jean-remiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jean-remiking/</guid>
      <description>École Normale Supérieure, Meta AI&#xA;Title of Jean-Rémi talk to be announced Abstract will appear here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>July 12th, 2024 - Gabrielle Girardeau</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/gabriellegirardeau/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/gabriellegirardeau/</guid>
      <description>Institut du Fer-à-Moulin&#xA;Neural mechanisms for emotional memory processing during sleep The gradual reinforcement of memories, called “consolidation”, is a process occurring partially during sleep and mediated by various patterns of coordinated neural activity. The formation of contextualized emotional memories involves a large network of structures, among which the hippocampus and the baso-lateral amygdala (BLA) are central. In the dorsal hippocampus, fast oscillations (sharp-wave ripples) during non-REM sleep mediate the consolidation of spatial memories through the reactivation of place cell activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 31st, 2024 - Matthew Chalk</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/matthewchalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/matthewchalk/</guid>
      <description>Vision Institute&#xA;Predicting visual neural responses: can we make better use of less data? How do sensory neurons respond to our surroundings? To answer this, we can train deep neural network models on recorded visual neuron responses (e.g., to presented movies/images), to predict responses to new stimuli. Performance is often limited by the data: the longer the recordings, the better the predictions; with short recordings, current models often fail. This is a problem since experiments are hard, and data often limited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality reduction beyond neural subspaces with slice tensor component analysis</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/slicetca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/slicetca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of gap junctions and clustered connectivity in emergent synchronisation patterns of inhibitory neuronal networks</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/mli-neural-mass/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signatures of task learning in neural representations</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/signaturesoflearningreview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar interneuron activity is triggered by reach endpoint during learning of a complex locomotor task</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/loco-reach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low tensor rank learning of neural dynamics</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/ltr-rnn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does the neocortex need the cerebellum for working memory?</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/journal-club/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellar granule cell axons support high-dimensional representations</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/granule-cells/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re-evaluating circuit mechanisms underlying pattern separation</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/pattern-separation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starter&#39;s Guide for students at BIASlab research team</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/research/starter-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 08:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/research/starter-guide/</guid>
      <description>This document is a starter&amp;rsquo;s guide for students who do an internship or graduate level (MSc, PhD) project with me. For the duration of your project you will become part of our BIASlab team of graduate students. I discuss here our research mission, our way of working, the tools we use and provide some links to key scientific papers that relate to our research. This guide is always a work in progress and each project will have its own goals and dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparse synaptic connectivity is required for decorrelation and pattern separation in feedforward networks</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/publication/sparse-connectivity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Cayco Gajic</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/alex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/alex/</guid>
      <description>I am a Junior Professor in the Departement D’Etudes Cognitives at ENS. My formal training lies squarely in applied mathematics, and I completed my PhD under the supervision of Eric Shea Brown at the University of Washington. Throughout my PhD I became increasingly interested in neuroscience, and wanted to learn more about the kinds of questions that were important to experimental neuroscientists. For my postdoc, I decided to join Angus Silver’s Angus Silver&amp;rsquo;s lab at UCL, where I began to focus on the cerebellar circuit while working closely with the experimentalists in his team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heike Stein</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/heike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/heike/</guid>
      <description>Since 2020, I am a postdoc with Alex Cayco Gajic at the Group for Neural Theory. Before that, I obtained my PhD from the Universitat de Barcelona, Spain, where I worked with Albert Compte to understand how NMDA receptor dysfunction affects working memory by altering prefrontal attractor dynamics.&#xA;In my postdoc, I am diving into the fields of motor learning and naturalistic behavior, the cerebellum, and how the cerebellum interacts with the neocortex to guide behavior and learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helen Todd</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/helen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/helen/</guid>
      <description>I am currently doing a PhD under the co-supervision of Boris Gutkin and Alex Cayco-Gajic at ENS Paris. My thesis focuses on modelling rapid synchronisation of interneurons in the cerebellum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mattia Della Vecchia</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/mattia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/mattia/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student at the Group for Neural Theory at Ecole Normale Supérieure in Paris . I have interests at the interface of Computational Neuroscience and Artificial Intelligence.&#xA;I performed my bachelor internship in the laboratory of Luca Berdondini at Italian Institute of Technology on large-scale neural recordings, spike sorting, and clustering. My master thesis focused on stochastic gradient descent methods for training recurrent neural networks inspired by biological findings under the supervision of Vincent Hakim at LPENS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/post/my-first-post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/post/my-first-post2/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networking Night Neural Networking Night establishes a platform for regular interactions and dialogue within the Ile-de-France Systems and Computational Neuroscience community. We propose an innovative and engaging project where a scientific seminar meets social interaction, the “Neural Networking Night”: Elevate the understanding of the brain in a social setting at a Neuroscience Seminar in “Le Piano Vache” pub (8 Rue Laplace, 75005 Paris), an iconic student pub in the academic 5th arrondissement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.&#xA;Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Ninou</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris under the joint supervision of Alex Cayco Gajic and Jonathan Kadmon.&#xA;My work focuses on the dynamics of learning in biologically plausible neural networks. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in the Hebbian dynamics of learning, its involvement in representational drift and potential applications to AI systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Agueci</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/member/leo/</guid>
      <description>I am a Ph.D. in the Group for Neural Theory at ENS in Paris. I am currently working on probing the cerebello-cortical loop during motor learning and behavior through mMachine learning and mathematical techniques. Previously, I was a research assistant in the group of Andrea Calimera, EDA, Politecnico di Torino, working in machine learning techniques application on predictive maintenance in the MADEin4 and R3-PowerUP european projects, and on development of neural network properties verification algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mission of the group</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/organizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/organizers/</guid>
      <description>Who organizes Neural Networking Night? Neural Networking Night is currently organized by Alex Cayco Gajic (LNC2, ENS, PSL), Srdjan Ostojic (LNC2, ENS, PSL) and Michael Graupner (SPPIN, Université Paris Cité).&#xA;It emerged from SysNeuroDrinks or Laboiratoire, which was created by Alex and Michael in the beginning of 2023 as informal, monthly gathering of the Systems and Computational Neuroscience Communities.&#xA;SysNeuroDrinks/Laboiratoire was further developped with input from Brice Bathellier, Jean-Baptiste Masson and Srdjan Ostojic to become Neural Networking Night in September 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mission of the group</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/overview/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview The overarching goal of our team is to understand how neural populations represent behavior and change over learning, using mathematical modelling and through development of data-driven methods.&#xA;We currently have openings - contact Alex if you are interested in joining the team!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The misson of the Neural Networking Night</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>What is Neural Networking Night? Neural Networking Night (NNN) establishes a platform for regular interactions and dialogue within the Ile-de-France Systems and Computational Neuroscience community. We propose an innovative and engaging project where a scientific seminar meets social interaction, the “Neural Networking Night”: Elevate the understanding of the brain in a social setting at a Neuroscience Seminar in “Le Piano Vache” pub (8 Rue Laplace, 75005 Paris), an iconic student pub in the academic 5th arrondissement.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
