<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neural Network Night</title>
    <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Neural Network Night</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Neural Networking Night, 2024 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dec 13th, 2024 - Sophie Bagur</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sophiebagur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sophiebagur/</guid>
      <description>ESPCI Paris&#xA;The role of bodily feedback in prefrontal regulation of fear states We have all introspectively sampled the tie between our body and our emotions and multiple lines of evidence demonstrate the tight correlations between brain–body interactions and affective states. However, the question of the specificity and causality of this link has remained unresolved since it was first epitomized by the historical James-Cannon debate. In the past few years, the possibility of manipulating bodily feedback in the mouse has driven insight into the underlying physiological mechanisms from multiple labs [1-3].</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jan 10th, 2025 - Jean-Rémi King</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jean-remiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jean-remiking/</guid>
      <description>École Normale Supérieure, Meta AI&#xA;AI and the Brain: the unexpected similarities and the remaining differences As AI systems now generate plausible texts and images, one may wonder whether these machines process information similarly to us. In this talk, we will discuss how this question is scientifically approached in the new field of &amp;lsquo;Neuro-AI&amp;rsquo;. The experimental results in the past decade highlight unexpected similarities, whereby computer vision algorithms learn to transform images through a hierarchy of representations that map onto the visual hierarchy in our cortex, and where a similar convergence can also be observed with large language models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feb 7th, 2025 - Laura Dugué</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/lauradugue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/lauradugue/</guid>
      <description>INCC, Université Paris Cité&#xA;Traveling Waves in Human Brain Neural oscillations have been observed across scales, species and recording methods. Recently, researchers have focused on their spatial organization across the cortex. Traveling Waves patterns, specifically, correspond to monotonic phase shifts in the direction of signal propagation and appear to play a role in cognitive functions. Identifying spatio-temporally consistent patterns, however, in non-invasively obtained human data (EEG or MEG recordings) poses significant technical challenges, such as source summation, volume conduction, and low signal-to-noise ratios, which complicate the interpretation of cortical activity from surface sensor measurements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mar 7th, 2025 - Kathleen Cho</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/kathleencho/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/kathleencho/</guid>
      <description>Institut du Cerveau, ICM&#xA;Prefontal interneuron function in cognitive control Rhythmic neural activity is thought to play a key role in the function of neural circuits, and within the prefrontal cortex (PFC), gamma oscillations have been associated with higher cognitive functions such as attention, memory, and cognitive control. Gamma oscillations in the PFC are mediated by a specific class of inhibitory interneurons that can be identified based on either their fast-spiking electrophysiological properties or expression of calcium-binding protein parvalbumin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apr 4th, 2025 - Fani Koukouli</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/fannykoukouli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/fannykoukouli/</guid>
      <description>Institut de Psychiatrie et Neurosciences Paris, IPNP&#xA;Cholinergic modulation of cortical inhibitory circuits and its dysfunction in psychiatric disorders The neocortex is essential for all cognitive functions, facilitated by the complex interplay of neuronal networks formed through synaptic interactions among various neuron types. In this context, inhibitory interneurons play a critical role in coordinating cortical activity. These inhibitory circuits are regulated by a variety of neuromodulators, with acetylcholine standing out for its significant control over cortical dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 2nd, 2025 - Sebastien Wolf</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sebastienwolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/sebastienwolf/</guid>
      <description>ENS&#xA;Title to be announced </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jun 13th, 2025 - Jean-Baptiste Masson</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeanbaptistemasson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeanbaptistemasson/</guid>
      <description>Institut Pasteur&#xA;Embodied neuroAI with drosophila larva Animals are not free-floating neural networks that perform classification tasks. Our body, the temporal continuity of our actions, and our sensory word shape the property and the computing of biological neural networks. Advances in Drosophila genetic manipulation, neural connectomics, and amortised inference (acceleration of the sampling procedure using neural networks) have allowed us to study small neural circuits&amp;rsquo; organisation, structure, and function. We still have a limited understanding of the forces organising small neural circuits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jul 4th, 2025 - João Barbosa</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/joaobarbosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/joaobarbosa/</guid>
      <description>Institute de Neuromodulation, Sainte-Anne&#xA;Distributed computations for flexible cognition </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sep 6th, 2024 - Guy Bouvier</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/guybouvier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/guybouvier/</guid>
      <description>Institut des Neurosciences Paris‑Saclay&#xA;The Mouse Primary Visual Cortex: Where Vision Meets Motion Many of the sensory organs that enable us to perceive the world around us are located on our head, for example, the eyes. To accurately represent our surroundings, sensory systems in the brain must combine their primary source of sensory information, e.g. visual signals, with information about head movements in space. The vestibular organs, located in the inner ear, provide this information by transforming head motion into neural signals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>July 12th, 2024 - Gabrielle Girardeau</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/gabriellegirardeau/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/gabriellegirardeau/</guid>
      <description>Institut du Fer-à-Moulin&#xA;Neural mechanisms for emotional memory processing during sleep The gradual reinforcement of memories, called “consolidation”, is a process occurring partially during sleep and mediated by various patterns of coordinated neural activity. The formation of contextualized emotional memories involves a large network of structures, among which the hippocampus and the baso-lateral amygdala (BLA) are central. In the dorsal hippocampus, fast oscillations (sharp-wave ripples) during non-REM sleep mediate the consolidation of spatial memories through the reactivation of place cell activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 31st, 2024 - Matthew Chalk</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/matthewchalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/matthewchalk/</guid>
      <description>Vision Institute&#xA;Predicting visual neural responses: can we make better use of less data? How do sensory neurons respond to our surroundings? To answer this, we can train deep neural network models on recorded visual neuron responses (e.g., to presented movies/images), to predict responses to new stimuli. Performance is often limited by the data: the longer the recordings, the better the predictions; with short recordings, current models often fail. This is a problem since experiments are hard, and data often limited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oct 4th, 2024 - Charlotte Le Mouel</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/charlottelemouel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/charlottelemouel/</guid>
      <description>Institut Systèmes Intelligents et de Robotique - ISIR&#xA;Sensorimotor coordination of balance The agility of humans and other animals relies on their ability to maintain balance during movement. This is a complex task requiring the integration of neurophysiology and biomechanics. In this talk, I show that young healthy adults use simple control strategies to maintain balance during standing and walking. Moreover, when standing and walking on the hands, gymnasts employ the same biomechanical strategies for balance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nov 8th, 2024 - Jérémie Barral</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeremiebarral/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/project/jeremiebarral/</guid>
      <description>Institut de l&amp;rsquo;Audition&#xA;Feedforward propagation along the mouse auditory pathway How spikes propagate along multiple layer networks has been extensively studied with computational models. Feedforward networks are a prominent model able to transmit information rapidly, but these networks have been difficult to isolate in the intact mammalian brain. Here, we focus on the auditory network which is characterized by multiple connected relays. We used sound and optogenetic stimulations to drive the auditory periphery and monitored neuronal activity at two locations along the auditory pathway simultaneously, using large-scale electrophysiological recordings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/post/my-first-post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/post/my-first-post2/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networking Night Neural Networking Night establishes a platform for regular interactions and dialogue within the Ile-de-France Systems and Computational Neuroscience community. We propose an innovative and engaging project where a scientific seminar meets social interaction, the “Neural Networking Night”: Elevate the understanding of the brain in a social setting at a Neuroscience Seminar in “Le Piano Vache” pub (8 Rue Laplace, 75005 Paris), an iconic student pub in the academic 5th arrondissement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.&#xA;Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mission of the group</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/organizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/organizers/</guid>
      <description>Who organizes Neural Networking Night? Neural Networking Night is currently organized by Alex Cayco Gajic (LNC2, ENS, PSL), Srdjan Ostojic (LNC2, ENS, PSL), João Barbosa (Institute for Neuromodulation, Cognitive Neuroimaing Lab - The Computational Brain, Neurospin) and Michael Graupner (SPPIN, Université Paris Cité).&#xA;It emerged from SysNeuroDrinks or Laboiratoire, which was created by Alex and Michael in the beginning of 2023 as informal, monthly gathering of the Systems and Computational Neuroscience Communities in The Bombardier bar (2 Pl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The misson of the Neural Networking Night</title>
      <link>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neuralnetworkingnight.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>What is Neural Networking Night? Neural Networking Night (NNN) establishes a platform for regular interactions and dialogue within the Ile-de-France Systems and Computational Neuroscience community. We propose an innovative and engaging project where a scientific seminar meets social interaction, the “Neural Networking Night”: Elevate the understanding of the brain in a social setting at a Neuroscience Seminar in “Le Piano Vache” pub (8 Rue Laplace, 75005 Paris), an iconic student pub in the academic 5th arrondissement.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
